healthways.com 2016-05-14

# Healthways.com Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**

Welcome to the Healthways, Inc. (“Healthways”) website available at “www.healthways.com” (this “Site”). This Statement discloses the Privacy Policy (this “Policy”) for this Site and describes how we collect, protect and use information we receive from visitors to our Site.  Healthways has created this Policy in order to demonstrate and inform you of our firm commitment to privacy.  This Policy applies only to information collected through this Site and not to information collected offline or through any other websites (even if affiliated with Healthways).

Translations on this Site are provided for convenience only. The English version of the Privacy Policy and Terms of Use shall apply. The Privacy Policy and Terms of Use shall be governed by and construed in accordance with United States law, and Healthways makes no representation that this Site is appropriate or available for use in locations outside of the United States.  

_Se aplicará la versión inglesa de la Política de privacidad y las Condiciones de uso. La Política de privacidad y las Condiciones de uso se regirán e interpretarán conforme a la legislación de Estados Unidos; Healthways no se pronuncia en ningún sentido acerca de la idoneidad o disponibilidad de uso de este sitio web fuera de Estados Unidos._

_La version anglaise des dispositions générales de la protection des données et des conditions d’utilisation devra s’appliquer.  Les dispositions générales de la protection des données et les conditions générales devront être régies par la loi des Etats-Unis et interprétées selon celle-ci, et Healthways ne garantit pas que ce site soit approprié et disponible pour l’utilisation dans des endroits situés en-dehors des Etats-Unis._

_Rechtlich verbindlich ist allein die englische Version der Datenschutzrichtlinie und der Nutzungsbedingungen.  Die Datenschutzrichtlinie und die Nutzungsbedingungen unterliegen dem Recht der Vereinigten Staaten von Amerika und sind in Übereinstimmung mit diesem auszulegen. Healthways macht keine Zusicherungen, dass die Website für die Nutzung außerhalb der Vereinigten Staaten geeignet oder verfügbar ist._

Last updated and effective as of December 7, 2009.

THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

There are two kinds of information websites can obtain about you: 

_(1) Anonymous Information:_  “Anonymous Information” is aggregate data that websites use to administer their sites. It may include such information as your browser type or your Internet Protocol (IP) address. Healthways may from time to time retain third parties to help us collect and aggregate Site customer information. 

IP Addresses. An IP address is a unique string of numbers that is assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider. Web servers automatically identify your computer by its IP address. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our Site, avoid hacking attacks on the Site’s server, and may use it to gather broad demographic, geographic, and industry information. We do not link IP addresses to any personally identifiable information, even if such information is voluntarily provided by a user. 

Cookie Information. As is the case with many websites, our Site uses a technology called “cookies”, which are small data files that are downloaded onto your computer. The use of cookies is standard on the Internet, and allows us to tailor your visits to our Site to your individual preferences.  We may also contract with third party service providers who assign cookies and/or web beacons to conduct site tracking for us. These companies use cookies solely to provide us with aggregate data about Site traffic. Although most web browsers automatically accept cookies, you can change your browser to prevent cookies or notify you whenever you are sent a cookie. Even without accepting a cookie, you can still access most of the features on our Site. 

_(2) Personally Identifiable Information:_  “Personally Identifiable Information” is any information that personally identifies you, such as your name, email address or your telephone number. Sometimes this personal information is needed when you submit a resume or when you contact us.  We may ask you to provide us with personal information on a voluntary basis in certain areas of our Site. In particular, you may be asked to provide the following information:

Email Correspondence. Scattered throughout the Site are links or forms that can be used to contact Healthways so you can comment, make a complaint, make suggestions and ask questions. Your contact information, such as name, address, email address may be required on these forms so we can address our answer in a mannerly way. Healthways may put such information on file, but does not currently share, sell, license or transmit this information with third parties without express authorization from you. 

Newsletters and Other Communications.  We offer visitors to this Site the opportunity to sign up to receive newsletters or other email communications from this Site.  In order to sign up for these communications, we may ask for contact information, such as name, address and email address.  We also may offer the opportunity for you to receive mailings from our partners that we think may be of interest to you.  

Forums and Public Comments.  The Site includes several opportunities for you to post or upload public comments.  Please note that such comments are intended to be publicly shared and any information you include in such comments may be made available through the Site.  In addition, the Site from time to time offers the opportunity to publicly comment through the use of third party social media services, i.e. Twitter or Facebook.  Should you provide information in connection with these services, your username may also be required and made publicly available.  

HOW WE USE GATHERED INFORMATION

The information you share with us may be used in a few ways:

_(1) Anonymous Information_ :  Anonymous Information is used internally for Site administration, troubleshooting and to help improve the quality of this Site and its design. We may share such aggregated, non-personally identifiable information, such as demographics, with existing and prospective business partners and advertisers.  We never connect aggregate information with Personally Identifiable Information, and none of the Anonymous Information we share will contain any information that identifies you individually.

_(2) Personally Identifiable Information:_   Personally Identifiable Information collected by Healthways may be used for purposes including administration of the Site and communications with you. In all cases, however, we will only use your information as permitted by law and our customer contracts.  In addition, we may from time to time contract with third parties to assist us in maintaining and managing our customer information.  In such instances, we advise these companies not to retain, store, share, or use Personally Identifiable Information for any secondary purposes.  We also may disclose Personally Identifiable Information if we are required to do so by law or we in good faith believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law or with legal process; (b) protect and defend our rights and property; (c) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of the Site; or (d) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public. Please note that we may not provide you with notice prior to disclosure in such cases. 

OPT-OUT

We support the right of our visitors to choose. You will be given the right to opt-out of receiving any promotional materials about Healthways whenever you are asked to provide Personally Identifiable Information on this Site. If you do not opt-out at that time, but later decide that you do not wish to receive future communications of this nature you can contact us at webmaster@healthways.com or at the address provided below, indicating that you no longer want to receive information relating to this Site.

ACCESS AND CORRECTION

You have certain rights to know about the Personally Identifiable Information that Healthways holds about you and gathered through this Site, including the right to correct, amend or delete the information that Healthways has on file if it is incorrect. If you wish to exercise these rights please contact us by email or postal mail at the addresses below. 

SECURITY

This Site incorporates safeguards to protect the security, integrity and privacy of the personal information we have collected.  We have put in place reasonable precautions to protect information from loss, misuse and alteration, including Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and database encryption. While on a secure page, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Microsoft Internet Explorer and Mozilla Firefox becomes locked, as opposed to unlocked, or open, when you are just “surfing”.  

Security of information communicated by or to us over the Internet is of utmost concern to us; however, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  Please note that your email, like most, if not all, non-encrypted Internet communications, may be accessed and viewed by other Internet users, without your knowledge and permission, while in transit to us.  For that reason, to protect your privacy, please do not use email to communicate information to us that you consider confidential. While we strive to protect your personal information, Healthways cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or through this Site. Once we receive your transmission, we will use reasonable efforts to ensure its security on our internal systems.  Depending on the nature of the inquiry, your communication may be discarded or archived.  If you wish, you may contact us instead via telephone at the numbers provided throughout our Site.

DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION THROUGH BUSINESS TRANSFERS

As we continue to develop our business, we may buy, merge or partner with other companies or businesses, and in so doing, acquire customer information.  In such transactions, user information may be among the transferred assets. Similarly, in the event that a portion or substantially all of Healthways’ assets are sold or transferred to a third party, customer information (including Personally Identifiable Information) would likely be one of the transferred business assets. 

OUR COMMITMENT TO CHILDREN'S PRIVACY

Protecting the privacy of children is very important to us. The Children's Online Privacy and Protection Act of 1998 (“COPPA”) defines a “Child” as anyone under the age of 13.  Healthways strictly adheres to COPPA. For that reason, we do not collect or maintain information obtained through our Site from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our Site is structured to attract anyone under 13.

EXTERNAL LINKS

This Site may provide links to various websites that we do not control. When you click on one of these links, you will be transferred out of our Site and connected to the website of the organization or company that you selected. We are not responsible for the nature, quality or accuracy of the content or opinions expressed on such websites, and such websites are not investigated, monitored or checked for quality, accuracy or completeness by us. Inclusion of any linked website on this Site does not imply or express an approval or endorsement of the linked website by us, or of any of the content, opinions, products or services provided on these websites. Even if an affiliation exists between our Site and a third-party website, we exercise no control over linked sites. Each of these linked sites maintains its own independent privacy and data collection policies and procedures.  While Healthways expects its partners and affiliates to respect the privacy of our users, Healthways cannot be responsible for the actions of third parties.  If you visit a website that is linked to from our Site, we encourage you to consult that website's privacy policy before providing any personal information and whenever interacting with any website. 

CONSENT AND MODIFICATIONS TO PRIVACY STATEMENT

This Site is controlled, operated and administered entirely within the United States.  By using this Site, you signify your agreement to the terms of this Policy. If you do not agree with this Policy, please do not disclose any personal information through this Site.  This Policy and the use of this Site are governed by Tennessee law.  Any claim related to the Site or this Policy shall be brought in a federal or state court in Nashville, Tennessee, within one year after the claim arises. Users of the Site consent to the exclusive jurisdiction and venue of such courts as the most convenient and appropriate for the resolution of disputes concerning this Policy. This Policy and the notices outlined herein are not intended to and do not create any contractual or other legal rights in or on behalf of any third party. 

SPECIAL NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS

Under the California Civil Code, residents of the State of California that have provided any Personally Identifiable Information to Healthways have the right to request a list of all third parties to which Healthways has disclosed Personally Identifiable Information during the preceding year for direct marketing purposes. Alternatively, the law provides that if Healthways has a privacy policy that gives either an opt-out or opt-in choice for use of Personally Identifiable Information by third parties (such as advertisers or affiliated companies) for marketing purposes, Healthways may instead provide you with information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options.  Healthways qualifies for the alternative option; it has established this Policy that provides you with details on how you may either opt-out or opt-in to the use of your Personally Identifiable Information by third parties for direct marketing purposes. 

If you are a California resident and request information about how to exercise your third party disclosure choices, please send a request to info@healthways.com with a preference on how our response to your request should be sent.

MODIFICATIONS TO PRIVACY POLICY

Healthways may modify this Policy at any time, at its discretion, and modifications are effective upon being posted on this Site. You are responsible for reviewing this Policy periodically to ensure that you are aware of any changes to it. 

ACCOUNT REVISIONS, REVOKING AND DELETING PERSONAL INFORMATION

We welcome your questions, comments and all feedback pertaining to your privacy or any other issue with regard to this Site. 

At any time, you may ask us to cease further use of your email address to send you correspondence, and direct us to delete any Personally Identifiable Information you have supplied.  Although it is not always possible to remove or modify such information, we will make reasonable efforts to do so. If you have given us information for one of those third parties we mentioned above and we have already passed it on, we may not be able to delete or change the information. 

In the event that you have given us Personally Identifiable Information in the past and then have second thoughts or want to update it, or if you have any other questions regarding this Policy or this Site, you may contact us at:  info@healthways.com
